Seán Blake, PhD

Astrophysics Researcher

About

Mail

blakese@tcd.ie

I am a motivated astrophysics researcher with 8 years of experience in **data analysis** and **scientific computing**, currently based at the NASA Goddard Space Flight Center. I am experienced with **machine learning**, data visualisation, manipulating large datasets and technical writing. I am seeking to apply my skill set to a data science/analyst role.

Web & Git

seanblake.ie

github.com/TerminusEst

Computing

- Python
- Numpy
 - Scipy
- Scikit-Learn
 - Linux
 - LATEX

Publications

orcid.org/0000-0001-9042-3557

Interests

Computers ==

Board Games

Poker 🗐

Running 🐔

Piano III

Skills

Data Analysis

- Extensive experience with **Python** both in developing code for scientific applications and teaching others. Also developed data-processing software for magnetic observatories (e.g. **Magie.ie**).
- Experienced with analysing large datasets, **machine learning**, time-series analysis, numerical physics simulations and web-scraping.

Communication

- Published multiple articles in academic journals, technical reports for engineers and presented at international conferences.
- Experience teaching physics and scientific computing to students.

Work Experience

2018-now Postdoctoral Researcher at NASA GSFC

Research extreme geomagnetic storms and their effect on power grids. Perform numerical physical simulations and analyse terabytes of output data using Python. Also scrape and process data from websites.

2017-2018 Postdoctoral Researcher at Trinity College Dublin

Gathered and processed geophysical data around Ireland as part of SWEMDI: the Space Weather Electromagnetic Database for Ireland.

2016-2018 **Director of CodifyDublin.com**

Founded Codify Ltd. which provided data science and computer programming workshops in Dublin. Designed curriculum, organised classes and taught approximately 150 students and professionals.

2014-2016 Workshop Leader with Student2Scientist.org

Ran educational computer science and physics workshops for secondary level students and teachers. Produced Junior Cert Short Course.

Education

2013-2017 Ph.D. in Astrophysics.

Trinity College Dublin, Ireland

2014-2015 Postgraduate Certificate in Statistics

Trinity College Dublin, Ireland

2009-2013 B.A. Mod. in Astrophysics, II.I